<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="console-application">
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <id>io.github.bkbilly.lnxlink</id>
  <name>LNXlink</name>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <developer id="io.github.bkbilly">
    <name>bkbilly</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://bkbilly.gitbook.io/lnxlink</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/issues</url>
  <url type="donation">https://github.com/sponsors/bkbilly</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink</url>
  <summary>Manage Linux machine with MQTT</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      LNXlink is a Linux companion app that seamlessly integrates your system with external applications like Home Assistant. It uses MQTT, a lightweight messaging protocol, to enable real-time data exchange and remote control capabilities.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Sensors: Automatically discover sensors that monitor and control the system.</li>
      <li>Home Assistant: Uses MQTT Autodiscovery to create entities and shows if update is required.</li>
      <li>No sudo required: No need to be root user to install and use, unless used on server setup.</li>
      <li>Easily expanded: Any new module is automatically imported and custom modules can be added.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/d6e42e9/images/preview.png</image>
      <caption>A caption</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <provides>
    <binary>lnxlink</binary>
  </provides>
  <categories>
    <category>System</category>
    <category>Monitor</category>
  </categories>
  <icon type="stock">io.github.bkbilly.lnxlink</icon>
  <releases>
    <release version="2026.7.0" date="2026-07-13">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases/tag/2026.7.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>2026.7.0</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fingerprint scanner module</li>
          <li>Include/exclude options for interfaces module</li>
          <li>Configuration option for a custom logging directory</li>
          <li>Compatibility with older loginctl JSON output</li>
          <li>Excluded entries are now automatically deleted from Home Assistant</li>
          <li>dasbus dependency dropped</li>
          <li>asyncio standard library requirement dropped</li>
          <li>Build dependencies bumped for better stability</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2026.6.0" date="2026-06-02">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases/tag/2026.6.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>2026.6.0</p>
        <ul>
          <li>MQTT: Connect through the Home Assistant API - great for Nabu Casa users or anyone who doesn't want to expose their MQTT broker</li>
          <li>LWT Sensor: Track when your device goes offline with the new availability sensor</li>
          <li>Current User: New sensor showing who is currently logged in</li>
          <li>Update Entities: New button to manually refresh all Home Assistant entities</li>
          <li>Systemd: Run lnxlink as a user service</li>
          <li>Bash: New select entity type - expose a dropdown driven by a shell command</li>
          <li>Bash: Set device_class and state_class on custom sensors for better HA integration</li>
          <li>Notifications: Use custom text IDs to update or close notifications by name</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2026.2.0" date="2026-01-31">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases/tag/2026.2.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>2026.2.0</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add interactive module selection, watch changes, clipboard support, mouse scrolling, and an Arch Linux AUR package.</li>
          <li>Improve Wayland support for brightness, screenshots, active window, fullscreen, and screen control modules.</li>
          <li>Fix unsupported module startup, media playback stalls, disk I/O filtering, and multi-key send keys handling.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2025.12.0" date="2025-12-21">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases/tag/2025.12.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>2025.12.0</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add advanced mouse input, Wayland input support, improved notifications, non-retainable MQTT topics, and Steam library configuration.</li>
          <li>Relax keyboard hotkey configuration and improve module initialization error handling.</li>
          <li>Fix Docker controls, hotkeys, battery discovery names, and MQTT environment variable credentials.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2025.10.0" date="2025-10-11">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases/tag/2025.10.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>2025.10.0</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add Docker update entities, topic cleanup on shutdown, autodiscovery prefix configuration, and detailed disk usage options.</li>
          <li>Improve LWT updates, sensor availability behavior, and media playback titles.</li>
          <li>Fix play media, screen control, and invalid MQTT topic characters.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2025.7.0" date="2025-07-09">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases/tag/2025.7.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>2025.7.0</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add device tracking, BeaconDB Wi-Fi tracking, extra UPower battery attributes, and development Docker builds.</li>
          <li>Replace Dasbus with Jeepney and improve system monitor stability.</li>
          <li>Fix Bluetooth output parsing and Disk IO initialization.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2025.6.0" date="2025-05-31">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases/tag/2025.6.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>2025.6.0</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add Wake On LAN, Wayland idle support, Bluetooth battery attributes, Docker suspend support, and module-defined settings.</li>
          <li>Improve PipeWire audio selection, battery filtering, media volume control, and dependency updates.</li>
          <li>Fix Docker integration, MQTT queue startup, boot selection, system updates, Bluetooth wildcard names, and blocking sudo commands.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2025.5.0" date="2025-05-01">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases/tag/2025.5.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>2025.5.0</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add Docker GUI app support, environment variables for sensitive values, configurable bash command timeouts, and logging level control.</li>
          <li>Replace dasbus with jeepney, support off bash checks, and split core code into multiple files.</li>
          <li>Fix MQTT reconnects, system updates in non-English locales, module discovery updates, and Bluetooth and Steam modules.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2025.2.0" date="2025-03-01">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases/tag/2025.2.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>2025.2.0</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add support for multiple media players and Arch installation.</li>
          <li>Fix battery names with special characters and GI dependency requirements.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2024.8.2" date="2024-08-17">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases</url>
      <description>
        <p>SystemD</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add SystemD use inside flatpak with DBUS</li>
          <li>Defaults configuration to ~/Documents/LNXlink/config.yaml</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2024.8.1" date="2024-08-16">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases</url>
      <description>
        <p>Run without configuration options</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Defaults configuration to ~/Documents/lnxlink.yaml</li>
          <li>Add Docker containers</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2024.8.0" date="2024-08-05">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/bkbilly/lnxlink/releases</url>
      <description>
        <p>First Flatpak Release</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Easy installation</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
